<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xiaoxiong Weng | AutoAI Lab</title>
    <link>/author/xiaoxiong-weng/</link>
      <atom:link href="/author/xiaoxiong-weng/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Xiaoxiong Weng</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/logo_hufbce6705a566d43a9610d78203895d17_430824_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Xiaoxiong Weng</title>
      <link>/author/xiaoxiong-weng/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>FourStr: When Multi-sensor Fusion Meets Semi-supervised Learning</title>
      <link>/publication/23-fourstr-icra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/23-fourstr-icra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
This research proposes a novel semi-supervised learning framework FourStr (Four-Stream formed by two two-stream models) that focuses on the improvement of fusion and labeling efficiency for 3D multi-sensor detector. FourStr adopts a multi-sensor single-stage detector named adaptive fusion network (AFNet) as the backbone and trains it through the semi-supervision learning (SSL) strategy Stereo Fusion. Note that multi-sensor AFNet and SSL Stereo Fusion can benefit each other. On the one hand, the Four-stream composed of two AFNets naturally provides rich inputs and large models for SSL Stereo Fusion. While other SSL works have to use massive augmentation to obtain rich inputs, and deepen and widen the network for large models. On the other hand, by the novel three fusion stages and Loss Pruning, Stereo Fusion improves the fusion and labeling efficiency for AFNet. Finally, extensive experiments demonstrate that FourStr performs excellently on outdoor dataset (KITTI and Waymo Open Dataset) and indoor dataset (SUN RGB-D), especially for the small contour objects. And compared to the fully-supervised methods, FourStr achieves similar accuracy with only 2% labeled data on KITTI (or with 50% labeled data on SUN RGB-D).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FocusTR: Focusing on Valuable Feature by Multiple Transformers for Fusing Feature Pyramid on Object Detection</title>
      <link>/publication/22-focustr-iros/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/22-focustr-iros/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The feature pyramid, which is a vital component of the convolutional neural networks, plays a significant role in several perception tasks, including object detection for autonomous driving. However, how to better fuse multi-level and multi-sensor feature pyramids is still a significant challenge, especially for object detection. This paper presents a FocusTR (Focusing on the valuable features by multiple Transformers), which is a simple yet effective architecture, to fuse feature pyramid for the single-stream 2D detector and two-stream 3D detector. Specifically, FocusTR encompasses several novel self-attention mechanisms, including the spatial-wise boxAlign attention (SB) for low-level spatial locations, context-wise affinity attention (CA) for high-level context information, and level-wise attention for the multi-level feature. To alleviate self-attention’s computational complexity and slow training convergence, FocusTR introduces a low and high-level fusion (LHF) to reduce the computational parameters, and the Pre-LN to accelerate the training convergence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPD: Semi-Supervised Learning and Progressive Distillation for 3-D Detection</title>
      <link>/publication/22-spd-tnnls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/22-spd-tnnls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Current learning-based 3-D object detection accuracy is heavily impacted by the annotation quality. It is still a challenge to expect an overall high detection accuracy for all classes under different scenarios given the dataset sparsity. To mitigate this challenge, this article proposes a novel method called semi-supervised learning and progressive distillation (SPD), which uses semi-supervised learning (SSL) and knowledge distillation to improve label efficiency. The SPD uses two big backbones to hand the unlabeled/labeled input data augmented by the periodic IO augmentation (PA). Then the backbones are compressed using progressive distillation (PD). Precisely, PA periodically shifts the data augmentation operations between the input and output of the big backbone, aiming to improve the network’s generalization of the unseen and unlabeled data. Using the big backbone can benefit from large-scale augmented data better than the small one. And two backbones are trained by the data scale and ratio-sensitive loss (data-loss). It solves the over-flat caused by the large-scale unlabeled data from PA and helps the big backbone prevent overfitting on the limited-scale labeled data. Hence, using the PA and data loss during SSL training dramatically improves the label efficiency. Next, the trained big backbone set as the teacher CNN is progressively distilled to obtain a small student model, referenced as PD. PD mitigates the problem that student CNN performance degrades when the gap between the student and the teacher is oversized. Extensive experiments are conducted on the indoor datasets SUN RGB-D and ScanNetV2 and outdoor dataset KITTI. Using only 50% labeled data and a 27% smaller model size, SPD performs 0.32 higher than the fully supervised VoteNetqi2019deep which is adopted as our backbone. Besides, using only 2% labeled data, compared to the other fully supervised backbone PV-RCNNshi2020pv, SPD accomplishes a similar accuracy (84.1 and 84.83) and 30% less inference time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMMF: Attention-Based Multi-Phase Multi-Task Fusion for Small Contour Object 3D Detection</title>
      <link>/publication/22-ammf-tits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/22-ammf-tits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Recently significant progress has been made in 3D detection. However, it is still challenging to detect small contour objects under complex scenes. This paper proposes a novel Attention-based Multi-phase Multi-task Fusion (AMMF) that uses point-level, RoI-level, and multi-task fusions to complement the disadvantages of LiDAR and camera, to solve this challenge. First, at the feature extraction phase, AMMF uses the Low and High-level Fusion with Matching Attention (LHF-MA) and efficient FPN (eFPN) to perform point-level fusion for cross sensors and single sensor, respectively. Instead of merging each level and using expensive 3D CNN like other methods, LHF-MA fuses low-level spatial location and high-level contextual feature of 2D CNN customized feature extractors and ignores the fusion of middle levels, reducing the computational cost. Then, at the proposal generation phase, Progressive Proposal Fusion (PPF) with learned attention map is used to perform coarse-to-fine RoI-level fusion, instead of only combining coarse-grained features at high-level of network. PPF using progressively increasing IoU thresholds could avoid overfitting and improve the performance. Note that the matching attentions and learned attention maps are utilized to weigh the priority of different sensors. Moreover, to solve the sparseness of point-wise fusion between LiDAR BEV and RGB image, AMMF uses multi-task fusion that generates pseudo-LiDAR from camera by depth estimation task, to guide this point-wise fusion. Finally, AMMF performs excellently for detecting small contour objects like pedestrians, cyclists, and distant cars. On the KITTI, AMMF finishes 3.62% improvements in the moderate instance for pedestrians. It achieves a 2.21% improvement in the &amp;gt;50 instance of LEVEL-2 level for vehicle on the Waymo Open Dataset. And AMMF is further verified on our customized dataset consisting of challenging scenarios like strong illumination and heavy shadow cases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Scale Fusion With Matching Attention Model: A Novel Decoding Network Cooperated With NAS for Real-Time Semantic Segmentation</title>
      <link>/publication/21-nas-attention-tits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/21-nas-attention-tits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
This paper proposes a real-time multi-scale semantic segmentation network (MsNet). MsNet is a combination of our novel multi-scale fusion with matching attention model (MFMA) as the decoding network and the network searched by asymptotic neural architecture search (ANAS) or MobileNetV3 as the encoding network. The MFMA not only extracts low level spatial features from multi-scale inputs but also decodes the contextual features extracted by ANAS. Specifically, considering the advantages and disadvantages of the addition fusion and concatenation fusion, we design multi-scale fusion (MF) that balances speed and accuracy. Then we creatively design two matching attention mechanisms (MA), including matching attention with low calculation (MALC) mechanism and matching attention with strong global context modeling (MASG) mechanism, to match varying resolutions and information of features at different levels of a network. Besides, the ANAS performs the deep neural network search by employing an asymptotic method and provide an efficient encoding network for MsNet, releasing researchers from those tedious mechanical trials. Through extensive experiments, we prove that MFMA, which can be applied to numerous recognition tasks, possesses excellent decoding ability. And we demonstrate the effectiveness and necessity of implementing the matching attention mechanism. Finally, the proposed two versions, MsNet-ANAS and MsNet-M achieve a new state-of-the-art trade-off between accuracy and speed on the CamVid and Cityscapes datasets. More remarkably, on the Nvidia Tesla V100 GPU, our MsNet-ANAS achieves 74.1% mIoU with the speed of 184.2 FPS on the CamVid while 72.9% mIoU with the speed of 119.9 FPS on the Cityscapes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
