<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Vision | AutoAI Lab</title>
    <link>/tag/computer-vision/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/computer-vision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Computer Vision</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/logo_hufbce6705a566d43a9610d78203895d17_430824_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Computer Vision</title>
      <link>/tag/computer-vision/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>MuTrans: Multiple Transformers for Fusing Feature Pyramid on 2D and 3D Object Detection</title>
      <link>/publication/23-mutrans-tip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/23-mutrans-tip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
One of the major components of the neural network, the feature pyramid plays a vital part in perception tasks, like object detection in autonomous driving. But it is a challenge to fuse multi-level and multi-sensor feature pyramids for object detection. This paper proposes a simple yet effective framework named MuTrans (Multiple Transformers) to fuse feature pyramid in single-stream 2D detector or two-stream 3D detector. The MuTrans based on encoder-decoder focuses on the significant features via multiple Transformers. MuTrans encoder uses three innovative self-attention mechanisms: Spatial-wise BoxAlign attention (SB) for low-level spatial locations, Context-wise Affinity attention (CA) for high-level context information, and high-level attention for multi-level features. Then MuTrans decoder processes these significant proposals including the RoI and context affinity. Besides, the Low and High-level Fusion (LHF) in the encoder reduces the number of computational parameters. And the Pre-LN is utilized to accelerate the training convergence. LHF and Pre-LN are proven to reduce self-attention’s computational complexity and slow training convergence. Our result demonstrates the higher detection accuracy of MuTrans than that of the baseline method, particularly in small object detection.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
