<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zhimin Chen | AutoAI Lab</title>
    <link>/author/zhimin-chen/</link>
      <atom:link href="/author/zhimin-chen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Zhimin Chen</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/logo_hufbce6705a566d43a9610d78203895d17_430824_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Zhimin Chen</title>
      <link>/author/zhimin-chen/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class-Level Confidence Based 3D Semi-Supervised Learning</title>
      <link>/publication/23-3d-semi-learning-wacv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/23-3d-semi-learning-wacv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Current pseudo-labeling strategies in 3D semi-supervised learning (SSL) fail to adaptively incorporate each class’s learning difficulty and learning status variance. In this work, we practically demonstrate that 3D unlabeled data class-level confidence can represent the learning status. Based on this finding, we present a novel class-level confidence based 3D SSL method. We firstly propose a dynamic thresholding method based on each class learning status obtained from class-level confidence. Then, a re-sampling strategy is designed to re-balance the learning status based on that the better learning status a class/instance has, the less sample probability it has. To show the generality of our method in 3D SSL task, we conduct extensive experiments on 3D SSL classification and detection tasks. Our method significantly outperforms state-of-the-art counterparts for both 3D SSL classification and detection tasks in all datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-To-End Training and Testing Gamification Framework to Learn Human Highway Driving</title>
      <link>/publication/22-end2end-driving-itsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/22-end2end-driving-itsc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
The current autonomous stack is well modularized and consists of perception, decision making and control in a handcrafted framework. With the advances in artificial intelligence (AI) and computing resources, researchers have been pushing the development of end-to-end AI for autonomous driving, at least in problems of small searching space such as in highway scenarios, and more and more photorealistic simulation will be critical for efficient learning. In this research, we propose a novel game-based end-to-end learning and testing framework for autonomous vehicle highway driving, by learning from human driving skills. Firstly, we utilize the popular game Grand Theft Auto V (GTA V) to collect highway driving data with our proposed programmable labels. Then, an end-to-end architecture predicts the steering and throttle values that control the vehicle by the image of the game screen. The predicted control values are sent to the game via a virtual controller to keep the vehicle in lane and avoid collisions with other vehicles on the road. The proposed solution is validated in GTA V games, and the results demonstrate the effectiveness of this end-to-end gamification framework for learning human driving skills.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal Semi-Supervised Learning for 3D Objects</title>
      <link>/publication/21-m2cp-learning-bmvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/21-m2cp-learning-bmvc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
In recent years, semi-supervised learning has been widely explored and shows excellent data efficiency for 2D data. There is an emerging need to improve data efficiency for 3D tasks due to the scarcity of labeled 3D data. This paper explores how the coherence of different modelities of 3D data (e.g. point cloud, image, and mesh) can be used to improve data efficiency for both 3D classification and retrieval tasks. We propose a novel multimodal semi-supervised learning framework by introducing instance-level consistency constraint and a novel multimodal contrastive prototype (M2CP) loss. The instance-level consistency enforces the network to generate consistent representations for multimodal data of the same object regardless of its modality. The M2CP maintains a multimodal prototype for each class and learns features with small intra-class variations by minimizing the feature distance of each object to its prototype while maximizing the distance to the others. Our proposed framework significantly outperforms all the state-of-the-art counterparts for both classification and retrieval tasks by a large margin on the modelNet10 and ModelNet40 datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Mapping and Stability Prediction for Autonomous Wheelchairs</title>
      <link>/publication/20-wheelchair-stability-cyber/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/20-wheelchair-stability-cyber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Autonomous wheelchairs can address a very large need in many populations by serving as the gateway to a much higher degree of independence and mobility capability. This is due to the fact that the big picture idea for autonomous wheelchairs integration into the transportation chain is to allow for individuals to be able to utilize the Intelligent wheelchair to reach the vehicle (regardless of terrain), mount into autonomous wheelchair that navigates to desired destination, and finally autonomous wheelchair dismounts. This will enable a higher degree of mobility for a handicapped population that experiences a large quantity of restrictions as a result of their circumstances. In order for this potential to be achieved numerous precautions must be integrated into the control system, such as stability maintenance. This paper focuses on mapping the environment through the use of a LiDAR sensor and predicting the stability of the given wheelchair. We utilize RTAB Mapping in combination with LiDAR odometry to construct a 3D map of the environment. Then Poisson reconstruction is deployed to convert the built 3D pointcloud into triangular mesh that allows for the norms to the surface to be calculated, which allows for stability prediction. This paper, not only outlines a novel pipeline but also deployed the pipeline on the recently released Intel RealSense L515 sensor and leverages its unique capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Modeling and Prediction of Rollover Stability for All-Terrain Vehicles</title>
      <link>/publication/20-gvsets-atv-stability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/20-gvsets-atv-stability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
With the particular passage capability, all-terrain vehicle (ATV) has been widely used for off-road scenarios. In this research, we conduct a lateral sway stability analysis for the suspension mechanism of a general vehicle and establish a mathematical model of static and dynamic stability based on the maximum lateral sway angle and lateral sway acceleration, by considering the combined angular stiffness of independent suspension, angular stiffness of the lateral stabilizer bar and vertical stiffness of tires. 3D point cloud data of a terrain environment is collected using an RGB-Depth camera, and a triangular topography map is constructed. The results in ADAMS show that the proposed stability model can accurately predict the critical tipping state of the vehicle, and the method deployed for real-world terrain modeling and simulation analysis is generalizable for the stability assessment of the interaction between ATV and real-world terrain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Wheelchair Stability While Crossing a Curb Using RGB-Depth Vision</title>
      <link>/publication/20-wheelchair-curb-icchp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/20-wheelchair-curb-icchp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Handicapped individuals often rely heavily on various assistive technologies including wheelchairs and the purpose of these technologies is to enable greater levels of independence for the user. In the development of autonomous wheelchairs, it is imperative that the wheelchair maintains appropriate stability for the user in an outdoor urban environment. This paper proposes an RGB-Depth based perception algorithm for 3D mapping of the environment in addition to dynamic modeling of the wheelchair for stability analysis and prediction. We utilize RTAB Mapping in combination with Poisson Reconstruction that produced triangular mesh from which an accurate prediction of the stability of the wheelchair can be made based on the normals and the critical angle calculated from the dynamic model of the wheelchair.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
