<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yingwei Li | AutoAI Lab</title>
    <link>/author/yingwei-li/</link>
      <atom:link href="/author/yingwei-li/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Yingwei Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/logo_hufbce6705a566d43a9610d78203895d17_430824_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Yingwei Li</title>
      <link>/author/yingwei-li/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class-Level Confidence Based 3D Semi-Supervised Learning</title>
      <link>/publication/23-3d-semi-learning-wacv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/23-3d-semi-learning-wacv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Recent state-of-the-art method FlexMatch firstly demonstrated that correctly estimating learning status is crucial for semi-supervised learning (SSL). However, the estimation method proposed by FlexMatch does not take into account imbalanced data, which is the common case for 3D semi-supervised learning. To address this problem, we practically demonstrate that unlabeled data class-level confidence can represent the learning status in the 3D imbalanced dataset. Based on this finding, we present a novel class-level confidence based 3D SSL method. Firstly, a dynamic thresholding strategy is proposed to utilize more unlabeled data, especially for low learning status classes. Then, a re-sampling strategy is designed to avoid biasing toward high learning status classes, which dynamically changes the sampling probability of each class. To show the effectiveness of our method in 3D SSL tasks, we conduct extensive experiments on 3D SSL classification and detection tasks. Our method significantly outperforms state-of-the-art counterparts for both 3D SSL classification and detection tasks in all datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
