<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yingwei Li | AutoAI Lab</title>
    <link>/author/yingwei-li/</link>
      <atom:link href="/author/yingwei-li/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Yingwei Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/logo_hufbce6705a566d43a9610d78203895d17_430824_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Yingwei Li</title>
      <link>/author/yingwei-li/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Domain Gap: Self-Supervised 3D Scene Understanding with Foundation Models</title>
      <link>/publication/23-domaingap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/23-domaingap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Foundation models have made significant strides in 2D and language tasks such as image segmentation, object detection, and visual-language understanding. Nevertheless, their potential to enhance 3D scene representation learning remains largely untapped due to the domain gap. In this paper, we propose an innovative methodology Bridge3D to address this gap, pre-training 3D models using features, semantic masks, and captions sourced from foundation models. Specifically, our approach utilizes semantic masks from these models to guide the masking and reconstruction process in the masked autoencoder. This strategy enables the network to concentrate more on foreground objects, thereby enhancing 3D representation learning. Additionally, we bridge the 3D-text gap at the scene level by harnessing image captioning foundation models. To further facilitate knowledge distillation from well-learned 2D and text representations to the 3D model, we introduce a novel method that employs foundation models to generate highly accurate object-level masks and semantic text information at the object level. Our approach notably outshines state-of-the-art methods in 3D object detection and semantic segmentation tasks. For instance, on the ScanNet dataset, our method surpasses the previous state-of-the-art method, PiMAE, by a significant margin of 5.3%.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class-Level Confidence Based 3D Semi-Supervised Learning</title>
      <link>/publication/23-3d-semi-learning-wacv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/23-3d-semi-learning-wacv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Recent state-of-the-art method FlexMatch firstly demonstrated that correctly estimating learning status is crucial for semi-supervised learning (SSL). However, the estimation method proposed by FlexMatch does not take into account imbalanced data, which is the common case for 3D semi-supervised learning. To address this problem, we practically demonstrate that unlabeled data class-level confidence can represent the learning status in the 3D imbalanced dataset. Based on this finding, we present a novel class-level confidence based 3D SSL method. Firstly, a dynamic thresholding strategy is proposed to utilize more unlabeled data, especially for low learning status classes. Then, a re-sampling strategy is designed to avoid biasing toward high learning status classes, which dynamically changes the sampling probability of each class. To show the effectiveness of our method in 3D SSL tasks, we conduct extensive experiments on 3D SSL classification and detection tasks. Our method significantly outperforms state-of-the-art counterparts for both 3D SSL classification and detection tasks in all datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
