<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peng Yin | AutoAI Lab</title>
    <link>/author/peng-yin/</link>
      <atom:link href="/author/peng-yin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Peng Yin</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/logo_hufbce6705a566d43a9610d78203895d17_430824_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Peng Yin</title>
      <link>/author/peng-yin/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling and Prediction of User Stability and Comfortability on Autonomous Wheelchairs With 3D Mapping</title>
      <link>/publication/22-wheelchair-thms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/22-wheelchair-thms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Traditional manual wheelchairs have a fixed seat with no movement or angle adjustment, which can seriously affect the user&amp;rsquo;s comfort and greatly limit user experience. However, the electric wheelchair relies on strong intelligence and automatic features; it can not only realize the multidegree freedom adjustment of the human body and the seat but also has a rich and powerful man–machine control interface, which greatly facilitates and improves the user experience. This study upgraded a Permobil C400-powered wheelchair with multisensor data fusion technology to enrich its terrain recognition, tipping stability, and comfortability prediction. The tipping stability modeling of the wheelchair dummy system is carried out using multibody dynamics and vibration mechanics to obtain the tipping stability limit and the comfort evaluation of the wheelchair vibration acceleration on the human body during travel. Based on the elevation mapping method, the wheelchair can estimate the terrain from the local point of view at any point in time. At the same time, the RGB-D depth camera is connected to the robot operating system (ROS) system, and the open-source algorithm package RTAB-MAP is used to complete the MAP construction and collect the 3-D point-cloud terrain data. Then, the real 3-D terrain files are generated through the point-cloud stitching technology for stability simulation of the wheelchair–human system. The tipping stability and comfort indexes of the wheelchair–human system when passing over different physical terrains can be obtained. The experimental results show that the IMU data located on the human chest agree well with the simulation analysis data and are suitable for a variety of complex real-terrain conditions, verifying the accuracy of the wheelchair–human system dynamics model and the feasibility of the simulation analysis process. Thus, this modeling and simulation method can predict wheelchair stability and user comfortability well and ensure a high-performance experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Self-Supervised Monocular Depth Learning with Sparse LiDAR</title>
      <link>/publication/21-depth-prediction-corl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/21-depth-prediction-corl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Self-supervised monocular depth prediction provides a cost-effective solution to obtain the 3D location of each pixel. However, the existing approaches usually lead to unsatisfactory accuracy, which is critical for autonomous robots. In this paper, we propose FusionDepth, a novel two-stage network to advance the self-supervised monocular dense depth learning by leveraging low-cost sparse (e.g. 4-beam) LiDAR. Unlike the existing methods that use sparse LiDAR mainly in a manner of time-consuming iterative post-processing, our model fuses monocular image features and sparse LiDAR features to predict initial depth maps. Then, an efficient feed-forward refine network is further designed to correct the errors in these initial depth maps in pseudo-3D space with real-time performance. Extensive experiments show that our proposed model significantly outperforms all the state-of-the-art self-supervised methods, as well as the sparse-LiDAR-based methods on both self-supervised monocular depth prediction and completion tasks. With the accurate dense depth prediction, our model outperforms the state-of-the-art sparse-LiDAR-based method (Pseudo-LiDAR++) by more than 68% for the downstream task monocular 3D object detection on the KITTI Leaderboard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSE-Match: A Viewpoint-Free Place Recognition Method With Parallel Semantic Embedding</title>
      <link>/publication/21-place-recognition-tits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/21-place-recognition-tits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Accurate localization on the autonomous driving cars is essential for autonomy and driving safety, especially for complex urban streets and search-and-rescue subterranean environments where high-accurate GPS is not available. However current odometry estimation may introduce the drifting problems in long-term navigation without robust global localization. The main challenges involve scene divergence under the interference of dynamic environments and effective perception of observation and object layout variance from different viewpoints. To tackle these challenges, we present PSE-Match, a viewpoint-free place recognition method based on parallel semantic analysis of isolated semantic attributes from 3D point-cloud models. Compared with the original point cloud, the observed variance of semantic attributes is smaller. PSE-Match incorporates a divergence place learning network to capture different semantic attributes parallelly through the spherical harmonics domain. Using both existing benchmark datasets and two in-field collected datasets, our experiments show that the proposed method achieves above 70% average recall with top one retrieval and above 95% average recall with top ten retrieval cases. And PSE-Match has also demonstrated an obvious generalization ability with limited training dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
