<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guoyong Yang | AutoAI Lab</title>
    <link>/author/guoyong-yang/</link>
      <atom:link href="/author/guoyong-yang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Guoyong Yang</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/logo_hufbce6705a566d43a9610d78203895d17_430824_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Guoyong Yang</title>
      <link>/author/guoyong-yang/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Wall-Climbing Robot for Concrete Construction Inspection</title>
      <link>/publication/22-wall-climbing-jfr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/22-wall-climbing-jfr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Human-made concrete structures require cutting-edge inspection tools to ensure the quality of the construction to meet the applicable building codes and to maintain the sustainability of the aging infrastructure. This paper introduces a wall-climbing robot for metric concrete inspection that can reach difficult-to-access locations with a close-up view for visual data collection and real-time flaws detection and localization. The wall-climbing robot is able to detect concrete surface flaws (i.e., cracks and spalls) and produce a defect-highlighted 3D model with extracted location clues and metric measurements. The system encompasses four modules, including a data collection module to capture RGB-D frames and inertial measurement unit data, a visual–inertial navigation system module to generate pose-coupled keyframes, a deep neural network module (namely InspectionNet) to classify each pixel into three classes (background, crack, and spall), and a semantic reconstruction module to integrate per-frame measurement into a global volumetric model with defects highlighted. We found that commercial RGB-D camera output depth is noisy with holes, and a Gussian-Bilateral filter for depth completion is introduced to inpaint the depth image. The method achieves the state-of-the-art depth completion accuracy even with large holes. Based on the semantic mesh, we introduce a coherent defect metric evaluation approach to compute the metric measurement of crack and spall area (e.g., length, width, area, and depth). Field experiments on a concrete bridge demonstrate that our wall-climbing robot is able to operate on a rough surface and can cross over shallow gaps. The robot is capable to detect and measure surface flaws under low illuminated environments and texture-less environments. Besides the robot system, we create the first publicly accessible concrete structure spalls and cracks data set that includes 820 labeled images and over 10,000 field-collected images and release it to the research community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Neural Network based Visual Inspection with 3D Metric Measurement of Concrete Defects using Wall-climbing Robot</title>
      <link>/publication/19-visual-inspection-iros/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/19-visual-inspection-iros/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
This paper presents a novel metric inspection robot system using a deep neural network to detect and measure surface flaws (i.e., crack and spalling) on concrete structures performed by a wall-climbing robot. The system consists of four modules: robotics data collection module to obtain RGB-D images and IMU measurement, visual-inertial SLAM module to generate pose coupled key-frames with depth information, InspectionNet module to classify each pixel into three classes (back-ground, crack and spalling), and 3D registration and map fusion module to register the flaw patch into registered 3D model overlaid and highlighted with detected flaws for spatial-contextual visualization. The system enables the metric model of each surface flaw patch with pixel-level accuracy and determines its location in 3D space that is significant for structural health assessment and monitoring. The InspectionNet achieves an average accuracy of 87.64% for crack and spalling inspection. We also demonstrate our InspectionNet is robust to view angle, scale and illumination variation. Finally, we design a metric voxel volume map to highlight the flaw in 3D model and provide location and metric information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Robotic System Towards Concrete Structure Spalling and Crack Database</title>
      <link>/publication/17-spalling-crack-db-robio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/17-spalling-crack-db-robio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Concrete spalling and crack inspection is a labor intensive and routine task. However, it plays an important role in structure health monitoring (SHM) of civil infrastructures. Autonomous inspection with robots has been regarded as one of the best ways to reduce both error and cost. This paper presents an automated approach using Unmanned Aerial Vehicle(UAV) and towards a Concrete Structure Spalling and Crack database (CSSC), which is by far the first released database for deep learning inspection. We aim locate the spalling and crack regions to assist 3D registration and visualization. For deep inspection, we provide a complete procedure of data searching, labeling, training, and post processing. We further present a visual Simultaneously Localization and Mapping(SLAM) approach for localization and reconstruction. Comparative experiments and field tests are illustrated, results show that we can achieve an accuracy over 70% for field tests, and more than 93% accuracy with CSSC database.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
