<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>selected | AutoAI Lab</title>
    <link>/tag/selected/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/selected/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>selected</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/logo_hufbce6705a566d43a9610d78203895d17_430824_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>selected</title>
      <link>/tag/selected/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disentangling Object Motion and Occlusion for Unsupervised Multi-frame Monocular Depth</title>
      <link>/publication/22-dynamicdepth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/22-dynamicdepth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Conventional self-supervised monocular depth prediction methods are based on a static environment assumption, which leads to accuracy degradation in dynamic scenes due to the mismatch and occlusion problems introduced by object motions. Existing dynamic-object-focused methods only partially solved the mismatch problem at the training loss level. In this paper, we accordingly propose a novel multi-frame monocular depth prediction method to solve these problems at both the prediction and supervision loss levels. Our method, called DynamicDepth, is a new framework trained via a self-supervised cycle consistent learning scheme. A Dynamic Object Motion Disentanglement (DOMD) module is proposed to disentangle object motions to solve the mismatch problem. Moreover, novel occlusion-aware Cost Volume and Re-projection Loss are designed to alleviate the occlusion effects of object motions. Extensive analyses and experiments on the Cityscapes and KITTI datasets show that our method significantly outperforms the state-of-the-art monocular depth prediction methods, especially in the areas of dynamic objects. Our code will be made publicly available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class-Level Confidence Based 3D Semi-Supervised Learning</title>
      <link>/publication/23-3d-semi-learning-wacv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/23-3d-semi-learning-wacv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Current pseudo-labeling strategies in 3D semi-supervised learning (SSL) fail to adaptively incorporate each class’s learning difficulty and learning status variance. In this work, we practically demonstrate that 3D unlabeled data class-level confidence can represent the learning status. Based on this finding, we present a novel class-level confidence based 3D SSL method. We firstly propose a dynamic thresholding method based on each class learning status obtained from class-level confidence. Then, a re-sampling strategy is designed to re-balance the learning status based on that the better learning status a class/instance has, the less sample probability it has. To show the generality of our method in 3D SSL task, we conduct extensive experiments on 3D SSL classification and detection tasks. Our method significantly outperforms state-of-the-art counterparts for both 3D SSL classification and detection tasks in all datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Wall-Climbing Robot for Concrete Construction Inspection</title>
      <link>/publication/22-wall-climbing-jfr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/22-wall-climbing-jfr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Human-made concrete structures require cutting-edge inspection tools to ensure the quality of the construction to meet the applicable building codes and to maintain the sustainability of the aging infrastructure. This paper introduces a wall-climbing robot for metric concrete inspection that can reach difficult-to-access locations with a close-up view for visual data collection and real-time flaws detection and localization. The wall-climbing robot is able to detect concrete surface flaws (i.e., cracks and spalls) and produce a defect-highlighted 3D model with extracted location clues and metric measurements. The system encompasses four modules, including a data collection module to capture RGB-D frames and inertial measurement unit data, a visual–inertial navigation system module to generate pose-coupled keyframes, a deep neural network module (namely InspectionNet) to classify each pixel into three classes (background, crack, and spall), and a semantic reconstruction module to integrate per-frame measurement into a global volumetric model with defects highlighted. We found that commercial RGB-D camera output depth is noisy with holes, and a Gussian-Bilateral filter for depth completion is introduced to inpaint the depth image. The method achieves the state-of-the-art depth completion accuracy even with large holes. Based on the semantic mesh, we introduce a coherent defect metric evaluation approach to compute the metric measurement of crack and spall area (e.g., length, width, area, and depth). Field experiments on a concrete bridge demonstrate that our wall-climbing robot is able to operate on a rough surface and can cross over shallow gaps. The robot is capable to detect and measure surface flaws under low illuminated environments and texture-less environments. Besides the robot system, we create the first publicly accessible concrete structure spalls and cracks data set that includes 820 labeled images and over 10,000 field-collected images and release it to the research community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Self-Supervised Monocular Depth Learning with Sparse LiDAR</title>
      <link>/publication/21-depth-prediction-corl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/21-depth-prediction-corl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Self-supervised monocular depth prediction provides a cost-effective solution to obtain the 3D location of each pixel. However, the existing approaches usually lead to unsatisfactory accuracy, which is critical for autonomous robots. In this paper, we propose FusionDepth, a novel two-stage network to advance the self-supervised monocular dense depth learning by leveraging low-cost sparse (e.g. 4-beam) LiDAR. Unlike the existing methods that use sparse LiDAR mainly in a manner of time-consuming iterative post-processing, our model fuses monocular image features and sparse LiDAR features to predict initial depth maps. Then, an efficient feed-forward refine network is further designed to correct the errors in these initial depth maps in pseudo-3D space with real-time performance. Extensive experiments show that our proposed model significantly outperforms all the state-of-the-art self-supervised methods, as well as the sparse-LiDAR-based methods on both self-supervised monocular depth prediction and completion tasks. With the accurate dense depth prediction, our model outperforms the state-of-the-art sparse-LiDAR-based method (Pseudo-LiDAR++) by more than 68% for the downstream task monocular 3D object detection on the KITTI Leaderboard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal Semi-Supervised Learning for 3D Objects</title>
      <link>/publication/21-m2cp-learning-bmvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/21-m2cp-learning-bmvc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
In recent years, semi-supervised learning has been widely explored and shows excellent data efficiency for 2D data. There is an emerging need to improve data efficiency for 3D tasks due to the scarcity of labeled 3D data. This paper explores how the coherence of different modelities of 3D data (e.g. point cloud, image, and mesh) can be used to improve data efficiency for both 3D classification and retrieval tasks. We propose a novel multimodal semi-supervised learning framework by introducing instance-level consistency constraint and a novel multimodal contrastive prototype (M2CP) loss. The instance-level consistency enforces the network to generate consistent representations for multimodal data of the same object regardless of its modality. The M2CP maintains a multimodal prototype for each class and learns features with small intra-class variations by minimizing the feature distance of each object to its prototype while maximizing the distance to the others. Our proposed framework significantly outperforms all the state-of-the-art counterparts for both classification and retrieval tasks by a large margin on the modelNet10 and ModelNet40 datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Method, Apparatus and Computer Program Product for Mapping and Modeling a Three Dimensional Structure</title>
      <link>/publication/20-mapping-patent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/20-mapping-patent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Embodiments described herein may provide a method for generating a three-dimensional vector model of the interior of a structure. Methods may include: receiving sensor data indicative of a trajectory; receiving sensor data defining structural surfaces within a structure; generating a three-dimensional point cloud from the sensor data defining structural surfaces within the structure; segmenting the three-dimensional point cloud into two or more segments based, at least in part, on the sensor data indicative of trajectory; generating a three-dimensional surface model of an interior of the structure based on the segmented three-dimensional point cloud with semantic recognition and labelling; and providing the three-dimensional surface model of an interior of the structure to an advanced driver assistance system to facilitate autonomous vehicle parking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
