<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>selected | AutoAI Lab</title>
    <link>/tag/selected/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/selected/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>selected</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/logo_hufbce6705a566d43a9610d78203895d17_430824_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>selected</title>
      <link>/tag/selected/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Domain Gap: Self-Supervised 3D Scene Understanding with Foundation Models</title>
      <link>/publication/23-domaingap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/23-domaingap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Foundation models have made significant strides in 2D and language tasks such as image segmentation, object detection, and visual-language understanding. Nevertheless, their potential to enhance 3D scene representation learning remains largely untapped due to the domain gap. In this paper, we propose an innovative methodology Bridge3D to address this gap, pre-training 3D models using features, semantic masks, and captions sourced from foundation models. Specifically, our approach utilizes semantic masks from these models to guide the masking and reconstruction process in the masked autoencoder. This strategy enables the network to concentrate more on foreground objects, thereby enhancing 3D representation learning. Additionally, we bridge the 3D-text gap at the scene level by harnessing image captioning foundation models. To further facilitate knowledge distillation from well-learned 2D and text representations to the 3D model, we introduce a novel method that employs foundation models to generate highly accurate object-level masks and semantic text information at the object level. Our approach notably outshines state-of-the-art methods in 3D object detection and semantic segmentation tasks. For instance, on the ScanNet dataset, our method surpasses the previous state-of-the-art method, PiMAE, by a significant margin of 5.3%.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking 3D Geometric Feature Learning for Neural Reconstruction</title>
      <link>/publication/23-rethinking3d-iccv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/23-rethinking3d-iccv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Recent advances in neural reconstruction using posed image sequences have made remarkable progress. However, due to the lack of depth information, existing volumetric-based techniques simply duplicate 2D image features of the object surface along the entire camera ray. We contend this duplication introduces noise in empty and occluded spaces, posing challenges for producing high-quality 3D geometry. Drawing inspiration from traditional multi-view stereo methods, we propose an end-to-end 3D neural reconstruction framework CVRecon, designed to exploit the rich geometric embedding in the cost volumes to facilitate 3D geometric feature learning. Furthermore, we present Ray-contextual Compensated Cost Volume, a novel 3D geometric feature representation that encodes view-dependent information with improved integrity and robustness. Through comprehensive experiments, we demonstrate that our approach significantly improves the reconstruction quality in various metrics and recovers clear fine details of the 3D geometries. Our extensive ablation studies provide insights into the development of effective 3D geometric feature learning schemes. The code will be made publicly available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FourStr: When Multi-sensor Fusion Meets Semi-supervised Learning</title>
      <link>/publication/23-fourstr-icra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/23-fourstr-icra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
This research proposes a novel semi-supervised learning framework FourStr (Four-Stream formed by two two-stream models) that focuses on the improvement of fusion and labeling efficiency for 3D multi-sensor detector. FourStr adopts a multi-sensor single-stage detector named adaptive fusion network (AFNet) as the backbone and trains it through the semi-supervision learning (SSL) strategy Stereo Fusion. Note that multi-sensor AFNet and SSL Stereo Fusion can benefit each other. On the one hand, the Four-stream composed of two AFNets naturally provides rich inputs and large models for SSL Stereo Fusion. While other SSL works have to use massive augmentation to obtain rich inputs, and deepen and widen the network for large models. On the other hand, by the novel three fusion stages and Loss Pruning, Stereo Fusion improves the fusion and labeling efficiency for AFNet. Finally, extensive experiments demonstrate that FourStr performs excellently on outdoor dataset (KITTI and Waymo Open Dataset) and indoor dataset (SUN RGB-D), especially for the small contour objects. And compared to the fully-supervised methods, FourStr achieves similar accuracy with only 2% labeled data on KITTI (or with 50% labeled data on SUN RGB-D).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class-Level Confidence Based 3D Semi-Supervised Learning</title>
      <link>/publication/23-3d-semi-learning-wacv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/23-3d-semi-learning-wacv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Recent state-of-the-art method FlexMatch firstly demonstrated that correctly estimating learning status is crucial for semi-supervised learning (SSL). However, the estimation method proposed by FlexMatch does not take into account imbalanced data, which is the common case for 3D semi-supervised learning. To address this problem, we practically demonstrate that unlabeled data class-level confidence can represent the learning status in the 3D imbalanced dataset. Based on this finding, we present a novel class-level confidence based 3D SSL method. Firstly, a dynamic thresholding strategy is proposed to utilize more unlabeled data, especially for low learning status classes. Then, a re-sampling strategy is designed to avoid biasing toward high learning status classes, which dynamically changes the sampling probability of each class. To show the effectiveness of our method in 3D SSL tasks, we conduct extensive experiments on 3D SSL classification and detection tasks. Our method significantly outperforms state-of-the-art counterparts for both 3D SSL classification and detection tasks in all datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disentangling Object Motion and Occlusion for Unsupervised Multi-frame Monocular Depth</title>
      <link>/publication/22-dynamicdepth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/22-dynamicdepth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Conventional self-supervised monocular depth prediction methods are based on a static environment assumption, which leads to accuracy degradation in dynamic scenes due to the mismatch and occlusion problems introduced by object motions. Existing dynamic-object-focused methods only partially solved the mismatch problem at the training loss level. In this paper, we accordingly propose a novel multi-frame monocular depth prediction method to solve these problems at both the prediction and supervision loss levels. Our method, called DynamicDepth, is a new framework trained via a self-supervised cycle consistent learning scheme. A Dynamic Object Motion Disentanglement (DOMD) module is proposed to disentangle object motions to solve the mismatch problem. Moreover, novel occlusion-aware Cost Volume and Re-projection Loss are designed to alleviate the occlusion effects of object motions. Extensive analyses and experiments on the Cityscapes and KITTI datasets show that our method significantly outperforms the state-of-the-art monocular depth prediction methods, especially in the areas of dynamic objects. Our code will be made publicly available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Wall-Climbing Robot for Concrete Construction Inspection</title>
      <link>/publication/22-wall-climbing-jfr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/22-wall-climbing-jfr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Human-made concrete structures require cutting-edge inspection tools to ensure the quality of the construction to meet the applicable building codes and to maintain the sustainability of the aging infrastructure. This paper introduces a wall-climbing robot for metric concrete inspection that can reach difficult-to-access locations with a close-up view for visual data collection and real-time flaws detection and localization. The wall-climbing robot is able to detect concrete surface flaws (i.e., cracks and spalls) and produce a defect-highlighted 3D model with extracted location clues and metric measurements. The system encompasses four modules, including a data collection module to capture RGB-D frames and inertial measurement unit data, a visual–inertial navigation system module to generate pose-coupled keyframes, a deep neural network module (namely InspectionNet) to classify each pixel into three classes (background, crack, and spall), and a semantic reconstruction module to integrate per-frame measurement into a global volumetric model with defects highlighted. We found that commercial RGB-D camera output depth is noisy with holes, and a Gussian-Bilateral filter for depth completion is introduced to inpaint the depth image. The method achieves the state-of-the-art depth completion accuracy even with large holes. Based on the semantic mesh, we introduce a coherent defect metric evaluation approach to compute the metric measurement of crack and spall area (e.g., length, width, area, and depth). Field experiments on a concrete bridge demonstrate that our wall-climbing robot is able to operate on a rough surface and can cross over shallow gaps. The robot is capable to detect and measure surface flaws under low illuminated environments and texture-less environments. Besides the robot system, we create the first publicly accessible concrete structure spalls and cracks data set that includes 820 labeled images and over 10,000 field-collected images and release it to the research community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Self-Supervised Monocular Depth Learning with Sparse LiDAR</title>
      <link>/publication/21-depth-prediction-corl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/21-depth-prediction-corl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Self-supervised monocular depth prediction provides a cost-effective solution to obtain the 3D location of each pixel. However, the existing approaches usually lead to unsatisfactory accuracy, which is critical for autonomous robots. In this paper, we propose FusionDepth, a novel two-stage network to advance the self-supervised monocular dense depth learning by leveraging low-cost sparse (e.g. 4-beam) LiDAR. Unlike the existing methods that use sparse LiDAR mainly in a manner of time-consuming iterative post-processing, our model fuses monocular image features and sparse LiDAR features to predict initial depth maps. Then, an efficient feed-forward refine network is further designed to correct the errors in these initial depth maps in pseudo-3D space with real-time performance. Extensive experiments show that our proposed model significantly outperforms all the state-of-the-art self-supervised methods, as well as the sparse-LiDAR-based methods on both self-supervised monocular depth prediction and completion tasks. With the accurate dense depth prediction, our model outperforms the state-of-the-art sparse-LiDAR-based method (Pseudo-LiDAR++) by more than 68% for the downstream task monocular 3D object detection on the KITTI Leaderboard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
